what's up everybody Phil bman with Barb
ben.com and we are going to cover the
Arnold strongman and strong women
classic as well as all of the Arnold
Classic bodybuilding shows from the
Arnold sports festival in Columbus Ohio
that took place March 1st through 2nd
2024 if you want to see any of the
coverage and looking back at who won
each competition head over to Barb
ben.com and you'll see all of our
coverage from that event the 2024 Arnold
sports festival in Columbus Ohio
features competitive strongman and
strong women competition the Arnold
strongman Classic this year showcased
some of the sports alltime greates
including the long anticipated Return of
the 2018 World strongest man and
three-time Arnold strongman classic
Champion ha Thor the mountain bornon the
Icelandic strength Legend flew to
Columbus to test his static strength
against 2019 world Strongest Man Martin
Lees the 2020 world Strongest Man Alexi
novakov two time World strongest man
Champion Tom stolman and the reigning
defending world strongest man and Arnold
strongman classic Champion Mitchell
Hooper among some of the other sports
top best the Arnold strong women classic
featured the defending Champion Victoria
long who aimed to repeat her dominance
from the 23 edition of the show as well
as two-time world strongest women
Rebecca Roberts the 2018 World strongest
woman Andrea Thompson log lift world
record holder inz Koso and the rest of
the elite roster after five grueling
events that tested the static strength
for both divisions the winners were
Mitchell Hooper goes backto back for the
strongman and Angelica Jardine winning
of the United States for the first time
in her Arnold debut she scores the top
of the podium winning by a half point
over former world's strongest woman Olga
leasa
breaking it down by events the opening
event for both competitions was the max
Elephant bar deadlift now hathor bjon
was expected to come in he said that he
was going to lift 460 kg his world
record coming into the event was 474 kg
now we knew the defending Champion
Mitchell Hooper has an excellent
deadlift and he knew what his Mark was
he scored 431 kgs that was good enough
for the bronze position in the event
Bobby Thompson also a massive deadlifter
he didn't come out until his opening
lift of 436 kg he locked that out and
said I'm good no more that meant that H
Thor yson could win the opening event in
his return to competitive strongman he
called for 456 Kg on the bar he locked
that out and still had plenty in the
tank when the commentary team asked him
if he had enough to break his world
record he said that he believed he could
but wanted to save his energy for the
rest of the competition moving over onto
the women's side for the max deadlift it
was Andrea Thompson at 291 kg scoring a
silver medal and breaking the 300 kg
barrier was Lucy underdown that is a Max
Elephant bar deadlift world record
exceeding Victoria Longs from last year
unfortunately for Victoria long in this
event she was going to defend her title
but she suffered a bad hamstring injury
on her third attempt and that sidelined
her for the rest of the competition so
we knew after event one on the strong
women side that a new Champion would be
crowned moving over into the second
event the timber carry a big event for a
bunch of athletes on the strongman side
we knew Mitchell Hooper was going to
come in with a fast time we knew mat
Kish Kowski was going to come in with a
fast time he actually held the world
record coming into the event at 7
seconds so for on the men's side Matos
Kish Kowski did again perform excellent
in this event he scored a time of 8.69
seconds surprisingly half th the
mountain bjornson he comes in the last
time that he did this event back when he
was still competing in competitive
strongman he did not do well in this
event he struggled to find his leverage
Point moving up the incline and it was
not expected that he would do well in
this event however he scored a
blistering time of 8.4 seconds and put
to rest any any doubts that he was not
at the top of his game even after a
four-year Hiatus from the sport going
back over to Mitchell Hooper he knew
that this was an event that he thought
he could win he scored a time of 7.1
seconds the commentary team for a moment
thought that he may have broken the
world record but when the official time
came in it was oneth of a second behind
Kish kowsky time from last year but it
was still good enough for first place
points that meant that Mitchell Hooper
and hawthor Boron were in the top two
spots at the end of day one it was going
to be a battle between the title holder
and the biggest Challenger literally in
the competition on the women's side in
the timber carry Andrea Thompson 8.43
seconds scores gold nobody touches her
Hannah Lindsay 9.53 seconds she gets a
second place finish and is actually tied
with Rebecca Roberts who also scored a
time of 9.4 53 seconds if that's not
indicative of how close this event can
be literally to athletes at the same
time down to hundredths of a second so
at the end of day one Andrew Thompson on
top and on the men's side h beon on top
moving over to day two in the Webster
stones for the women Angelica Jardine
she's moving up the leaderboard on day
two she scores her first event win of
the competition in her debut she's got
something to say 27.94 meters in the
Webster Stones Rebecca Roberts uh
scaling back up after her day one
performance at
19.51% Thor bjornson still in the
running though he's still on top 10.72 M
and in third place Evan Singleton brings
his intensity he scores 10.62 M to score
the bronze in the event the fourth event
of the competition is where the strong
men and strong women differed the women
they did a heavy dumbbell press the men
they did the apollinis which is an axle
cleaning press on the women's side Sam
Bello she scores her first arold strong
woman classic event win with 84 kg for
two reps she was the only strong woman
to lift that weight next up was oash
shock she scored 80 kg at two reps and
Hannah Lindsay in third place she also
hit 80 kg with one rep tying with
Melissa peacock who's still in the mix
she scored one rep on 80 kgs as well
everybody else only lifted 70 kg or
below for the apoll wheels on the men's
side an undeniable feat of strength for
the champion Mitchell Hooper he scores
his third straight event win of the
competition with five reps nobody else
touched that mat kiskowski he comes in
second place scores four reps he was
tied with Tom stolman two time World
world Strongest Man Champion he scores
four reps he's still in the mix he
hasn't been in the running at the top of
the leaderboard but he's been in the top
of results for every competition so far
he's looking for a Podium position with
one event to go in the final event the
stones of strength essentially a ston
lifting medley showing off what you can
do with the stones on both the strong
woman and the strong man side in the
final event Angelica Jardine had worked
her way back up that if she beat ogali
asuk in the final event she would take
home the title Angelica Jardine scored
six stones and that was enough that was
two owns more than anybody else in the
competition she scores the overall win
by a half point a half point for the
United States athlete she scores her
first Arnold strongwoman Classic Victory
congratulations to her an epic
performance on day two to come from
behind and take the title down on the
men's side Mitchell Hooper essentially
had a runaway performance however he
needed to put it away in the stones of
strength it came down to hawor bornon
was he going to put on enough of a
performance in the final event to make
up for his lackluster two so far uh no
it was not to be done haor bjon could
not lift the first stone which
essentially was a block press of a heavy
Stone he could not do it he got no lift
he along with the majority of the
strongman field could not get past
Implement number one Mitchell Hooper
however he got through the first one he
then loaded a stone over the bar for the
second one he called out Arnold sarzo to
come to the stage to watch him lift one
more although he couldn't lift the third
Stone two stones in a time of 19.15
seconds was still enough to secure the
crown and the overall title matate
Kowski still in the mix at the top of
all of these Elite events he scored
second place overall he was the only
athlete to get past the second Stone on
the final event he scored five Stones
Tom stolman he got third place in the
event as the only other athlete to score
two stones and that was enough to secure
the bronze position over haor bjon on
the podium so Tom stman gets that third
place finish behind Matos kiskowski in
second and Mitchell Hooper in third in
first who goes back to back at the
Arnold strongman classic all this is to
say that when we see haor bjornson back
in competition at the Rogue which will
be in Aber Scotland it will be an epic
showing for the strong man who has
returned he was very impressive in his
strongman return most experts in the
space including me if I were to be
considered one did not have hawthor
bornon finishing on the podium while he
narrowly missed it in fourth place we we
meaning me thought that he might be
later lower down on the leaderboard at
after having a good deadlift event
nobody expected him to do what he did in
the timber carry it was a very
impressive return for the mountain and
we can only expect good things going
forward from him but until then Mitchell
Hooper's dominance continues as the
Arnold strongman classic Champion let's
move over to bodybuilding there are few
bodybuilding shows that match The
Prestige of the Arnold Classic
co-founded in 1989 by Jim lurmer and
seven time Mr Olympia Arnold Schwarz and
AER the competition has expanded from
one single bodybuilding show to include
seven divisions as it did in 2024 the
2024 Arnold Classic took place in the
only location it has called home for 35
years Columbus Ohio the action occurs at
the Arnold sports festival which is an
Uber Expo of Fitness Fanatics that
includes powerlifting and weightlifting
in Brazilian jiu-jitsu and an expo with
hundreds of vendors and of course the
iconic Arnold strongman and strongwoman
classic and Arnold Classic bodybuilding
competitions so let's dive right into
the results of the seven divisions that
competed at the Arnold Classic they were
split up three on day one four on day
two we're going to go through them in
order starting with the 2024 Fitness
International that this is a division
that competes across two rounds the
physique round and the routine round it
is unique in the bodybuilding space in
that way the physique round counts for
onethird of an athlete score and the
routine round counts for two-thirds of
an athlete score so jacn Baker who is a
top contender in this division across
every single top show she had an
incredible physique round in the
commentary team had her winning the show
until Ariel kadar's routine round put
all the doubts to rest Ariel Kadar she
goes for the three peat in Columbus
scores the $25,000 check and the routine
round coming in big for Ariel Kadar who
is dominant in Columbus moving over to
the wellness division this was the time
where we were going to see a rematch
from the Olympia it was Francy alamatos
versus Isabelle Nunes again they were so
narrowly close at the 2023 Olympia they
were split by one Point Matos of course
getting the win she's a three-time
wellness Olympia Champion the only
champion in that division since its
Inception but Nunes has been right on
her heels from the get-go and Nunes the
defending Champion she comes in and it
was as narrow as it could be once again
but Matos getting the nod from the
judges and the $10,000 check Matos on
top Nunes in second and Sandra Colorado
alal in fourth for the $4,000 check but
Matos continues her dominance in the
wellness division we can only expect
that going forward in the Olympia
somebody is going to have to to take it
from her because as of right now Matos
is the standard in Wellness moving over
to the Arnold Classic physique
competition this this division has been
dominated by chis Bumstead for the last
half decade the guy has been on top of
the Olympia every year it's the only
competition he's competed in but right
on his heels has been Ramon Roa now now
Ramon Dino has been the the contender
for Bumstead for the last two years he's
been the runnerup at the Olympia he's
the defending Arnold Classic champion
and it is seen that at some point Ramone
might be able to take Bumstead down that
day has not come yet but it was
anticipated that he would defend here in
Columbus but a massive upset if you can
call it that given what the physiques
look like on stage Wesley vissers he
comes down he scores the upset win over
Ramon in a call a head-to-head call out
that could see it going either way now
this was an upset from the commentary
team's point of view they thought
Ramon's physique just flows so
beautifully he's got an incredibly tight
waist but it was vissers who came in as
the larger athlete this time around he
scores the $60,000 check and puts
himself right into the mix at the top of
the division going into the Olympia
later this year against Bumstead against
Ramon and of course against ear K
cisinski who scored third place here at
the Arnold for the $220,000 check so
it's vissers then rone then ERS and we
will see them all compete against
Bumstead at the 2024 Olympia also
notably right off of the podium in
fourth place position Brion Ansley
hasn't lost a step he's still at the top
of of the division with those guys he is
going to also have have to work on what
he can do to face the taller larger
athletes in the division that he is
competing against moving over to the
2024 bikini International contest it was
Laura Lee shapos coming in as a two-time
defending Champion she had something to
say about where she stands in the Bikini
division after coming out of the 2023
Olympia and it was indeed a battle
between her and Amy Delgato in the final
call outs it was a very close show Amy
Delgado had had an incredible 2023
season winning multiple Pro shows but at
the end of the day narrow beating Amy
Delgato by one point was in fact shapos
who went back to back to back
congratulations to the three p champion
at the Arnold Classic moving over into
men's physique again this was an
incredibly tight battle between a lot of
athletes but it was a Brazilian finish
at the end Dogo Montenegro he went up
against venicius Matas Vera Lima in the
final it was those two guys in the
middle of the final call out bookended
by vtor Chavez and Chiron Holden those
were your top four in order but it was
Dogo mon
who took the title down due to an
incredibly dense musculature that had
the commentary team asking why he wasn't
moving into classic physique with his
size but Diogo Montenegro very
impressive physique he takes down the
Arnold Classic men's physique title for
the first time in his career in the
Arnold Classic wheelchair division it
has been dominated by exactly one man
and that is Harold Kelly for the last
six years he has been the Arnold Classic
wheelchair Champion he comes in he looks
great however the judges are not
favorable to him this year he dro drops
all the way down to fourth place that
might have been the most shocking
outcome thus far of the Arnold Classic
outside of Wesley V's upset over raone
that meant that Gabrielle andrulli was
expected to take the title as he is a
former Arnold Classic wheelchair
Champion down but he got second place
and in a huge turn of events rajes John
in his debut wins the Arnold Classic
title a very impressive physique from
him the athlete from India scores his
first Arnold Classic wheelchair title
and we will see more of him in the major
events as we go forward because he just
mixed up that division significantly
with his win moving over to the final
contest the Arnold Classic the men's
open we knew coming into the event that
it was going to be Samson Duda the
defending Champion versus 2022 Mr
Olympia Champion hadti chupan both of
these guys finished in the in the second
place for chupan and third place for
Duda at the 20123 Olympia behind Derrik
lindford it was a question of could
Samson Duda defend his title and show
that he is the number one Contender for
Lunsford going into the 2024 Olympia
that was not to be however as chupan
conditioning is just unparalleled in the
division chupan takes the title down of
the Arnold Classic Champion Duda comes
in second place although it was Titan
you could have seen it go either way
because of duda's size he is a dominant
force on stage just booming muscle mass
over the rest of the division but there
is not a midsection anywhere else in the
world like chupan he is absolutely
dialed in he was diced n and the
conditioning just made your eye go to
him every time they were in a
head-to-head call out against those two
or the other top athletes which were in
third place Rafael brandow and in fourth
place John Del Roa so going into the
2024 Olympia we know that Derek lford is
the guy to beat but hadu chupen seems to
have not lost the step even though he
got second place at the 2023 Olympia he
scores the win here at the 2024 arold
classic and will again be the number one
Contender as expected going into the
2024 Olympia however we can't count out
Samson do he came in looking excellent
and he will only get better as we get to
the big com competition later in 2024
and to close things out on top of the
fact that hadti chupan had an incredible
win over Samson Duda but both of those
guys are going to be very exciting to
watch heading into the 2024 Olympia
later this year Arnold swar and AER gave
everyone a go home present announcing
that for the 2025 Arnold Classic the
men's open Champion will not only win
the coveted title but in 2025 the prize
purse will go from 300 $1,000 to the
winner to
$500,000 for the winner a $200,000 prize
purse jump to the men's open champion at
the Arnold Classic so Heidi chupen takes
down the title of 2024 he gets $300,000
in the bank but next year if he defends
the title in 2025 he will be awarded
$500,000 that is the largest prize purse
in bodybuilding the Olympia Awards
$400,000 to the men's open Champion
Arnold Schwarzenegger laying down the
stakes he's saying that the Arnold
Classic in 2025 will have a winning
prize purse of $500,000 so there you
have it that's 2024 on the classic for
both the strong man strong women and the
bodybuilding divisions I'm Phil Blackman
for Barb and.com thank you for watching
our coverage all weekend and we will
catch you next
[Music]
time
he